<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-29">September 29, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title> ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK, LIMITED advertisement</title>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                <head>THE ANGLO-EGYPTIAN BANK, LIMITED.</head>
                <p>LONDON, PARIS ALEXANDRIA, CAIRO MALTA, GIBRALTAR, TANTAH, AND PORT SAID. </p>
                <p>Subscribed Capital JS1.500,000</p>
                <p> Paid up '' £ 500,000 </p>
                <p>Reserve Fund... 500,000</p>
                <p>The Anglo-Egyptian Bank. Limited, undertakes every description of banking
                    business on the most favourable conditions.</p>
                <p>Current accounts opened with commercial homes and private individuals in
                    conformity with the custom of Bankers. </p>
                <p>Fixed deposits for one year certain received at 8 per cent. per annum. Deposits
                    at interest for shorter periods are also received at rates to be agreed upon. </p>
                <p>Letters of Credit for the use of travellers are issued payable in all parts of
                    the World. </p>
                <p>Approved bills discounted. </p>
                <p>Bills, documentary invoices, etc, collected. </p>
                <p>Drafts and telegraphic transfers issued payable all over the World. </p>
                <p>Foreign exchange bought and sold. </p>
                <p>Advances made upon approved securities and upon cotton, cotton-seed, sugar and
                    other merchandise. </p>
                <p>The purchase and sale of stocks and shares on the London Stock Exchange; and on
                    the local and Continental Bourses, undertaken. </p>
                <p>Customers can deposit their valuables, bonds, etc., for safe custody in the
                    Bank's fire-proof strong-rooms, and the Bank will attend to the collection of
                    the coupons and drawn bonds so deporited as they fall due. </p>
                <p>Mercantile credits issued. </p>
                <p>Annuities, pensions, dividends, etc., collected. </p>
                <p>All farther particulars and information can be obtained on application. </p>
                <p>The officers and clerks of the Bank are pledged to secrecy as to the transactions
                    of customers. 18-9-905 </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
