<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
          <titleStmt>
              <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
              <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
              <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
              <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
              <edition>
                  <date when="2016-09-29">September 29, 2016</date>
              </edition>
          </editionStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
              <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
              <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
          </publicationStmt>
          <sourceDesc>
              <bibl>
                  <title>Hall's Sanitary Washable Distemper advertisement</title>
                  <date when="1905-07-11">July 11, 1905</date>
              </bibl>
          </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
          <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-hdi01">
              <head>Hall's Sanitary Washable Distemper</head>
              <p>Made in 70 Colors</p>
              <p>An artistic wall covering.</p>
              <p>This celebrated water paint is made in two qualities for Inside and Outside
                    work</p>
              <p>HALL’S SANITARY WASHABLE DISTEMPER is rapidly superseding wall papers in all
                    tastefully furnished homes. It is made in 70 artistic tints, and only requires
                    the addition of water to make it ready for use. It is quickly and easily applied
                    with a whitewash brush, with half the labour and at one third the cost of paint.
                    HALL’S DISTEMPER ensures cleanliness, and is pleasing to the eye. It appeals
                    alike to artistic and practical house decoration. HALL’S DISTEMPER is of special
                    value in hot climates. Owing to its cool, pleasing colours, great
                    weather-resisting and germ-destroying properties, it lends itself to every kind
                    of wall, wood, brick or stone coating, possessing all the advantages of paint,
                    colour- wash, and disinfectant at one third the cost of oil paint. It never
                    blisters in the hottest sun, and the fact that it can be washed adds greatly to
                    its sanitary advantages.</p>
              <p>Supplied in Tins and Iron Kegs.</p>
              <p>Sole Manufacturers :</p>
              <p>SISSONS BROTHERS &amp; Co., Ltd., HULL.</p>
              <p>Stocks are held In Cairo by FRANK RATCLIFFE, Sanitary Contractor and Engineer,
                    Sharia Saptieh.</p>
              <p>In Alexandria by RAMADAN YOUSSEF, Sanitary Contractor, Rue Sesostris.</p>
              <p>General Agents: GEORGE MORRIS &amp; Co.. Alexandria &amp; Cairo.</p>
          </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
