<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
          <titleStmt>
              <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
              <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
              <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
              <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
          </titleStmt>
          <editionStmt>
              <edition>
                  <date when="2016-09-29">September 29, 2016</date>
              </edition>
          </editionStmt>
          <publicationStmt>
              <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
              <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
          </publicationStmt>
          <sourceDesc>
              <bibl>
                  <title>Maple &amp; Co. advertisement</title>
              </bibl>
          </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
          <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
              <head>Maple &amp; Co.</head>
              <p>The Largest, and Most Convenient Furnishing Establishment in the World HUNDREDS
                    of THOUSANDS of POUNDS WORTH OF HIGH-CLASS FURNITURE, BEDSTEADS, BEDDING,
                    CUTLERY, CHINA, GLASS, SILVER WARE, CARPETS, CURTAINS, BLINDS, &amp;c., always
                    ready for immediate shipment. A house furnished throughout in three days.</p>
              <p>The “Cathcart ” Dining-Room Suite in Mahogany, Walnut or Fumed Oak, with brass
                    mountings, consists of 6 ft Sideboard with handsomely carved pediment and
                    panels, bevelled mirrors in back, lower portion usefully fitted with drawers,
                    cupboards and cellarette; 3 ft 6 in Silver Cabinet, extreme height 7 ft fitted
                    with clear glass shelves and mirrored back; 3 ft 6 in Dinner Wagon with two
                    drawers and cupboard; Dining Table 4 ft wide and extending to 8 ft long, with
                    extra leaves and patent screw; six very strong Dining Room Chairs with carved
                    backs, upholstered in best marone morocco: Price includes packing and delivery
                    F.O.B. London .. £70 0 0</p>
              <p>Separate prices on application</p>
              <p>“ONE of the SIGHTS of LONDON”</p>
              <p>Maple &amp; Co invite residents of Cairo, Alexandria, Damanhour, Tantah,
                    Mansourah, Damietta, Samahud, Rosetta, Miniah, Ismailla, Port Said, and
                    districts, when visiting London to walk through these spacious showrooms and
                    galleries, and see for themselves all the latest novelties and new productions.
                    MAPLE &amp; CO also send patterns of all kinds of material, and illustrations of
                    furniture, bedsteads, &amp;c., on application, and give Inclusive f.o.b.
                    estimates when desired.</p>
              <p>TOTTENHAM COURT ROAD LONDON ENGLAND</p>
          </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
