<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2017-04-13">April 13, 2017</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Peruna advertisement</title>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-per01">
                <head>Neglected Colds cause Consumption.</head>
                <head>THE WHITE SCOURGE</head>
                <p> MRS. ADDIE HARDING. MRS. MARY MEYER. MRS. FRANCES WILSON. </p>
                <p>PROBABLY every case of consumption begins with a cold. </p>
                <p>Consumption is generally classed as a hereditary disease, but consumption is not
                    hereditary. </p>
                <p>A constitutional weakness is inherited which renders one liable to consumption. </p>
                <p>Even people who have strong lungs may acquire consumption from a cold. </p>
                <p>Mrs. Addie Harding, 121 W, Brighton Ave., Syracuse, N. Y., writes: </p>
                <p>“I have been a user of Peruna for the last twelve years and can truthfully say
                    that there is no better medicine on earth. </p>
                <p>“A SURE PREVENTATIVE." </p>
                <p>“With me it is a sure preventative for colds and many other ills. In my home can
                    always be found a bottle of Peruna. Two or three times a year I am troubled with
                    my throat. </p>
                <p>"I always had to have the services of my physician two or three times in each
                    case. </p>
                <p>"Although a user of Peruna, I never thought of taking it for my throat until
                    about two years ago.</p>
                <p> "I tried Peruna to check it, and to my great delight I was not troubled with the
                    smothered and choked feeling and never have since. </p>
                <p>"I can check it every time with Peruna. </p>
                <p>"I certainly would not be without Peruna one minute." </p>
                <p>Mrs. Mary Meyer, Thomson avenue, near Shell Road, Winfield, L. L, N. Y., writes: </p>
                <p>"I have been annoyed with a cough for years. </p>
                <p>"Often it was so bad that I could not sleep half the night. Many people thought I
                    had consumption.</p>
                <p>CONSUMPTION WAS FEARED.</p>
                <p>"A woman recommended Peruna to me two years ago. I began to take Peruna and now I
                    am perfectly free from a cough, </p>
                <p>"I am glad to say that Peruna cured me entirely, I take Peruna occasionally when
                    I do not feel well and I also give it to my children. </p>
                <p>“Peruna is the best medicine for coughs and colds. I have told many people how
                    much Peruna has helped me.” </p>
                <p>A neglected cold is a well-worn path to consumption. </p>
                <p>Many a person catches cold and pays no attention to it. </p>
                <p>He scarcely recovers from the first cold when he takes the second.</p>
                <p>Still he gives it no heed, and possibly takes another cold, and so on. </p>
                <p>He doses himself with bromides, quinine and various expectorants. </p>
                <p>His case is catarrh, at this stage, and his case should be treated as catarrh. </p>
                <p>A common cold is acute catarrh. </p>
                <p>Finally, if the cold is allowed to continue, it becomes chronic catarrh. </p>
                <p>Mrs, Frances Wilson, 82 Nelson street, Clinton, Mass., writes: </p>
                <p>“Had you seen me at the time of my illness and now, you would not wonder that 1
                    take delight in sounding the praises of Peruna. </p>
                <p>“My ailment was a severe cold which attacked the bronchial tubes and lungs. </p>
                <p>“I followed your special directions and after using six bottles of Peruna I was
                    on my feet again.</p>
                <p>“I think Peruna a wonderful medicine." </p>
                <p>All colds, coughs, bronchitis, laryngtis and tonsilitis should be treated as
                    catarrh, as they are in reality catarrh. </p>
                <p>The success of Peruna in relieving these cases entirely depends upon the fact
                    that Peruna is a catarrh remedy. </p>
                <p>It relieves catarrh wherever located in the system. Whether in the throat,
                    bronchial tubes or lungs. </p>
                <p>CONSUMPTION PREVENTED.</p>
                <p>It has saved a multitude of peo-ple from consumption by eradicating catarrh
                    before it reaches the lungs. </p>
                <p>The tendency of catarrh of the throat or head is to spread downward to the lungs. </p>
                <p>If taken in time, Peruna will prevent these cases. </p>
                <p>We have in our files many testimonials from people who thought they were victims
                    of consumption, but have been permanently relieved by the faithful use of
                    Peruna. thus showing that catarrh was really the cause of their ailments.</p>
                <p>For special directions everyone should read “ The Ills of Life." a copy of which
                    surrounds each bottle. Peruna is for sale by all chemists and druggists at five
                    shillings per bottle or six bottles for twenty-five shillings. </p>
                <p>Those wishing direct correspondence with DR. Hartman and can wait the necessary
                    delay in receiving a reply should address Dr. S. B. HARTMAN, Columbus, Ohio,
                    U.S.A. </p>
                <p>The following wholesale druggist will supply the retail drug trade in Alexandria,
                    Egypt </p>
                <p>E. DEL MAR, </p>
                <p>Alexandria, Egypt</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
