<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2019-10-06">October 6, 2019</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Pe-ru-na advertisement</title>
                    <date when="1905-07-08">July 8, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-per03">
                <p>THOUSANDS OF FAIR WOMEN HERALD PRAISES FOR PE-RU-NA. </p>
                <p>(Catarrhal Dyspepsia and Nervous Prostration Makes Invalids of More Women Than
                    all other Diseases Combined.) </p>
                <p>Miss Anna Prescott</p>
                <p>Mrs. Leone Dolehan. </p>
                <p>Miss Louise Matt. </p>
                <table rows="1" cols="3">
                    <row>
                        <cell><p>Miss Anna Prescott, in a letter from 216 South Seventh street,
                                Minneapolis, Minn., writes: </p><p>"I was completely used up last
                                fall, my appetite had failed and I felt weak and tired all the time.
                                I took Peruna for five weeks, and am glad to say that I am
                                completely restored to health." – Anna Prescott. </p>Mrs. Leone
                            Dolehan, in a letter from the Commercial Hotel, Minneapolis, Minn.,
                            writes: <p>"For two month's my physician experimented with me trying to
                                cure a hard cold which settled in my stomach, caus-</p></cell>
                        <cell>
                            <p>ing inflammation and catarrh. I have now been well for six months,
                                and I give all the credit to Peruna.” – Mrs. Leone Dolehan. </p>
                            <p>Peruna will be found to effect an immediate and lasting cure in all
                                cases of systemic catarrh. It acts quickly and beneficially on the
                                diseased mucous membranes, and with healthy mucous membranes the
                                catarrh can no longer exist.</p>
                            <p>Miss Louise Matt, 1259 Van Buren St., Chicago, M., writes: </p>
                            <p>“Peruna is a most wonderful medicine for catarrhal and stomach
                                troubles.</p>
                            <p>I suffered so long with indigestion and dyspepsia, and tried many
                                things to cure me, without relief. I finally bought a bottle of
                                Peruna and in just six weeks I was entirely rid of my stomach
                                trouble."-Louise Matt.</p>
                        </cell>
                        <cell><p>A Letter From Mrs. Senater Warren. </p><p>The following letter is
                                from the wife of late Governor and now U. S. Senator, F. E. Warren
                                of Wyoming: </p><p>"I am constantly troubled with colds, cough,
                                etc., but thanks to your good medicine, Peruna, I always find a
                                prompt cure.”—Mrs. F. E. Warren. </p><p>If you do not derive prompt
                                and satisfactory results from the use of Peruna, write at once to
                                Dr. Hartman, giving full statement of your case and he will be
                                pleased to give you his valuable advice gratis.</p>Address Dr.
                            Hartman, President of The Hartman Sanitarium, Columbus, Ohio.</cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
                <p>For special directions everyone should read « THE ILLS OF LIFE," a copy of which
                    surrounds each bottle. Peruna is for sale by all chemists and druggists at five
                    shillings per bottle or six bottles for twenty-five shillings. </p>
                <p>Those wishing direct correspondence with Dr. HARTMAN and can wait the necessary
                    delay in receiving a reply should address Dr. S. B. HARTMAN, Columbus, Ohio,
                    U.S.A. </p>
                <p>The following wholesale druggist will supply the retail drug trade in Alexandria,
                    Egypt. </p>
                <p>MAX FISCHER,</p>
                <p>Alexandria, Egypt. </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
