<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Peyton Smith</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2019-10-12">October 12, 2019</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Standard Life Assurance Company advertisement</title>
                    <date when="1907-10-16">October 16, 1907</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-sla03">
                <head>THE STANDARD LIFE ASSURANCE CO.</head>
                <head>ESTABLISHED 1825.</head>
                <p>ACCUMULATED FUNDS £11,750,000.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">NEW SCHEMES OF ASSURANCE.</hi></p>
                <p>ENDOWMENT ASSURANCES with guaranteed bonus on survival of 2 per annum for each
                    100 of assurance.</p>
                <p>CHILDREN'S ENDOWMENTS at low rates, with return of all premiums paid in the event
                    of death before the given age is attained.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">EXAMPLES:</hi></p>
                <p>ENDOWMENT ASSURANCES WITH GUARANTEED BONUS ON SURVIVAL.-A, aged 30 next birthday,
                    with Good prospect of longevity, takes out a Policy of £1,000 under this table
                    for an Endowment Assurance payable at the age of 60 or earlier death, with a
                    Guaranteed Bonus of 40s. per cent per annum. If he survives the fixed term, the
                    annual premium for which will be £38:15:0. In the event of death within the 30
                    yearsm only the sum assured in the Policy is payable, viz:- £1,000, but if he
                    survives the term, he is entitled to receive besides £1,000, a Guaranteed Bonus
                    of 30 times 40s. per cent; i.c. £800, or in all £600; and similarly for other
                    periods and rates, Premiums can be paid quarterly or half-yearly if desired.</p>
                <p>CHILDREN'S ENDOWMENT.- An annual Premium of £18:1:3 will provide a child aged 1
                    next birthday with an Endowment of £500 on attaining the age of 21. In the event
                    of the child's death before the given age is attained, all the premiums paid to
                    the Company will be return to the parent. Premiums can be paid quarterly or
                    half-yearly if desired. Should the parent wish to discontinue the payment of
                    premiums, he can claim a surrender value of 90 per cent of all the annual
                    premiums paid by him, excepting the first, providing three full years premiums
                    have been paid and the transaction is completed while the Policy is in force.
                    Should the parent not wish to take the surrender value, he has the option, after
                    three full years' premiums have been paid, of receiving a Paid-up Policy for
                    such a proportion of the original Sum Assured as the number of payments made
                    bears to the whole number payable. If written application be made and the
                    transaction completed within the days of grace, and provided such proportion be
                    not less than £50.</p>
                <p>For Prospectus, Forms of Proposal and all particulars, apply to the STANDARD LIFE
                    OFFICE, STANDARD BUILDINGS, CAIRO.</p>
                <p><measure type="indexNo">30689-13-13</measure></p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
