<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="item" scope="advertisement">
    <p>Thos. Cook &amp; Son (Egypt), Ltd.</p>
    <p>Engineers, Boulac, Cairo. Alexandria.</p>
    <p> MECHANICAL AND ELECTRICAL ENGINEERS, ALSO SHIPBUILDERS, &amp;C., &amp;C. All
        classes of engineering work and supply of stores undertaken. Pontoon Dock
        for raising vessels of the largest size. </p>
    <p>BOULAC ENGINE WORKS</p>
    <p>Branches at Sharia Bab-El-Hadeed (CAIRO), ALEXANDRIA AND KHARTOUM.</p>
    <p>Sole agents in Egypt for</p>
    <p>RICHARD GARRETT &amp; SONS, LTD. Portable and semi-portable steam engines,
        Road rollers, threshing and straw-chopping machines. </p>
    <p>SHAND, MASON &amp; CO. Patent Steam and Manual Fire Engines.</p>
    <p>NOBEL'S EXPLOSIVES CO., LTD. Gelignits, Blasting Gelatine, detonators, safety
        fuse, etc. ‘‘Sporting Ballistite” and “Empire" Cartridges.</p>
    <p>GEO. ANGUS &amp; CO., LTD. Machine belting of every description, leather,
        rubber, cotton and Balata.</p>
    <p>TANGYES LIMITED (SOLE VENDORS.) Steam, Oil and Gas Engines, with Produce
        Plants, Pumps and Machinery of all description.</p>
    <p>CROMPTON &amp; Co., LTD. Dynamos, motors and electric machinery of all
        description.</p>
    <p>STOHWASSER &amp; WINTER PUTTIE LEGGING &amp; MILITARY EQUIPMENTS CORPORATION
        LTD. Agents for Jesse Ellis &amp; Co. Steam and Oil Motor Wagons.</p>
    <p>CHUBB &amp; SON'S LOCK &amp; SAFE CO. LTD Chubb's Steel Safes of all sizes on
        hand, the building of strong rooms undertaken.</p>
    <p>COCHRAN &amp; CO. ANNAN, LTD. The Cochran patent vertical boilers.</p>
    <p>THE SEAMLESS STEEL BOAT CO., LTD. Seamless steel boats fitted with any class
        of motor. </p>
    <p>THE COOPER STEAM DIGGER CO. LTD. Diggers made in size No. 5, 6, 8 and 12. </p>
    <p>Specialities: TANGYES’ GAS ENGINES with Producer Plants, COOPER PATENT STEAM
        DIGGER, specially suitable for small landowners.</p>
    <p>Telegraphic Address :"ENGINEER, CAIRO" and “ENGINEER, ALEXANDRIA." </p>
    <p>Works Office in town, Sharia Bab-El-Hadeed (Cairo).</p>
    <p>Alexandria Office and Stores, Abu Dirdar Street, No. 12. 10.12.905</p>
</div>
