<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2016-09-29">September 29, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Therapion advertisement</title>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                <p>A BROKEN-DOWN SYSTEM.</p>
                <p>This is a condition (or disease) to which doctors give many names, but which few
                    of them really understand. It it simply weakness—a break-down, as it were, of
                    the vital forces that sustain the system. No matter what may be its causes (for
                    they are almost numberless), its symptoms are much the same; the more prominent
                    being sleeplessness, sense of prostration or weariness, depression of spirits
                    and want of energy for all the ordinary affairs of life. Now, what alone is
                    absolutely essential in all such cases is increased vitality—vigour--</p>
                <p>VITAL STRENGTH &amp; ENERGY</p>
                <p>to throw off these morbid feelings, and experience proves that as night succeeds
                    the day this may be more certainly secured by a course of the celebrated
                    life-reviving tonic</p>
                <p>THERAPION No.3</p>
                <p>than by any other known combination. So surely as it is taken in accordance with
                    the printed directions accompanying it, will the shattered health be
                    restored,</p>
                <p>THE EXPIRING LAMP OF LIFE LIGHTED UP AFRESH,</p>
                <p>and a new existence imparted in place of what had so lately seemed worn-out,
                    "used up,” and valueless. This wonderful medicament is purely vegetable and
                    innocuous, is agreeable to the taste —suitable for all constitutions and
                    conditions, in either sex; and it is difficult to imagine a case of disease or
                    derangement, whose main features are those of debility, that will not be
                    speedily and permanently benefited by this never-failing recuperative essence,
                    which is destined to cast into oblivion everything that had preceded it for this
                    wide-spread and numerous class of human ailments.</p>
                <p>THERAPION</p>
                <p>is sold by the principal Chemists throughout the world. Price in England, 2 9
                    and 4/6. Purchasers should see that the word 'THERAPION' appears on British
                    Government Stamp (in white letters on a red ground) affixed to every package
                    by order of His Majesty’s Hon. Commissioners, and without which it is a
                    forgery.</p>
                <p>Sold by E. Del Mar, Alexandria, Cairo &amp; Port Said</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
