<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/out/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Will Hanley</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date when="2018-02-09">February 9, 2018</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Mackie's White Horse Cellar advertisement</title>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="advert" xml:id="deg-ad-whc02">
                <p> THE GREATEST care should be taken in what we eat and drink, yet we are too often
                    indifferent and careless, notwithstanding health depends on what we eat and
                    drink.</p>
                <p>In regard to drink nothing but the best should be taken. It costs no more than
                    the indifferent quality, if people would only ask for what they know is the best
                    Old Scotch Whisky is the most wholesome beverage yet known Mackie's Scotch
                    Whisky gives an undoubted guarantee to those who are not judges of quality.</p>
                <p> CITY ANALYSTS LABORATORY, </p>
                <p> 138 BATH STREET, </p>
                <p> GLASC0W, 8th October, 1906. </p>
                <p>I hereby certify that I have taken samples of every vatting of <hi rend="bold"
                        >Mackie's White Horse Celler</hi> Blend of Scotch Whisky used in bottling
                    during the month of September, and the results of my analyses indicate that it
                    conforms to the standard for Pot Still Scotch Whisky set up in the London case.
                    I am also of opinion that it is an old Whisky of excellent quality and flavour,
                    which has been well matured in wood.</p>
                <p> JOHN CLARK, Ph.D., F.C.S., F.I.C., </p>
                <p><hi rend="italic">Public Analyst for the City of Glasgow and the Counties of
                        Lanark, Renfrew, &amp;c.</hi></p>
                <p>N.B.—This Whisky is the same as supplied to the Red Cross Society, London, to the
                    House of Lords and House of Commons.</p>
                <p> N. SPATHIS, Agent. </p>
                <p>CAIRO and ALEXANDRIA.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
